Stanley Ogada

Senior Frontend Developer

Lagos, Nigeria
+234 915 659 5803 ● +234 706 594 9104
chineduogada@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/stanley-ogada
github.com/stanleyogada

SUMMARY

Senior front-end developer with over 5+ years of experience developing front-end web apps based on React.

Self-starter with a strong work ethic who approaches challenges with enthusiasm. I also find all these interesting: code reviewing, automated testing, pair-coding, chilling with teammates in video meetings, and estimating story points:).

I am looking forward to working in a remote, competitive, and demanding environment at this stage in my career.

SKILLS

Programming Languages, Tools, and Frameworks

- Typescript | Javascript (ES6+) | HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | LESS | Styled-Components
- React.js | Next.js | Redux | Jest | React-Testing-Library | Cypress | Axios | React-Query
- Chart.js | Material-UI | Chakra-UI | Bootstrap | TailwindCSS | Webpack | Story-book
- Git | Github | BitBucket | Node.js | NPM | Express.js | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | Heroku | Vercel
- Slack | Jira | Google Meets | Sentry | Trello | Travis-Cl | Circle-Cl | Split.IO

EXPERIENCE

BETTERPOOL, United States: Frontend Web Developer (contract via KANDA SOFTWARE)

SEP 2022 - JAN 2023 • 5 mos

- Under the direction of the product manager, features were quickly delivered to deployment while adhering to specific ticket goals and utilizing tools like automated tests and feature-flagging with Split. IO.
- Excellent communication skills were displayed while working independently and in small teams efficiently and effectively.
- Successfully dissected unfamiliar systems to demonstrate autonomy and troubleshooting prowess.
- Facilitated productive teamwork between the Czech Republic and the United States by working with teammates across time zones.

KANDA SOFTWARE, Newton - United States: Senior Frontend Developer (full-time)

MAY 2022 - **PRESENT**

- Worked as a contractor with teams from various locations, juggling multiple time zones successfully.
- Frontend technical interviews were conducted to evaluate and onboard new employees.
- Reduced delays and redundant components in existing projects by putting in place clean, reusable code.

INITS LIMITED, Lagos - Nigeria: Frontend Developer (contract)

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022 • 3 mos

- Used Jest and the React-Testing-Library to quickly implement new features using a TDD (Test-Driven Development) methodology.
- Each new feature had a minimum test coverage of 91%, ensuring reliable and robust code.
- I took on the management and handling of 4 React projects for a transportation app.
- Actively worked with project and product managers, as well as engineering partners, to turn concepts into features that were successfully deployed in production.

CRIBSTACK, Lagos - Nigeria: React Developer (contract)

FEB 2022 - APR 2022 • 3 mos

- Quickly implemented new features while adhering to a Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodology using Jest and the React-Testing-Library and maintaining more than 60% test coverage.
- Sentry was used to monitor and enhance component performance. Any problems or bugs were found and fixed, and the code was optimized by writing clear, reusable solutions to cut down on delays and redundancies.
- 100% type safety was achieved by creating type-safe utilities, hooks, and components using TypeScript, and code splitting were implemented using Webpack.

XANOTECH SOLUTIONS, Lagos - Nigeria: Frontend Developer (full-time)

SEP 2021 - FEB 2022 ● 6 mos

- Using CI/CD tools like CircleCl and GitHub Actions, I designed and implemented cross-platform frameworks to improve functionality and streamline pipeline integration.
- Played a significant part in improving the user experience across all supported client platforms, which led to a 5% increase in clients in just two months.
- Used tools like Trello, Slack, and Google Meet to facilitate close collaboration with engineers and designers and to show leadership, effective communication, and active listening skills.
- Efficiently fixed bugs and problems across the entire Grooming Centre codebase, ensuring quick and efficient troubleshooting.

SILVERDREAM RESOURCES INT'L, Lagos - Nigeria: React Engineer (Contract)

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022 • 11 mos

- Managed releases, kept an eye on logs, and produced reports to efficiently find and fix bugs, ensuring that production was updated and fixed on schedule. streamlined workflows by using tools like Sentry, Travis-Cl, Git, and GitHub.
- Played a significant part in the product design and decision-making processes, aiding in the development of the best user journeys.
- New features were swiftly implemented using a Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodology and tools like Jest and React-Testing-Library.

CONSULTINGBORD LIMITED, Lagos - Nigeria: React Engineer (Contract)

APR 2018 - NOV 2018 • 8 mos

- Built the entire frontend web app, including the following features: employee management, leave management, data importation as .xls files, employee training schedules, reporting, and complex data visualization (using D3.js and Chart.js).
- Wrote up to 67% of unit/integration test coverage using Jest and React-Testing-Library.

FLORINTECH COMPUTER COLLEGE, Lagos - Nigeria: Junior Web Developer (Full-time)

OCT 2017 - MAR 2018 • 6 months

- Supported the learning and professional development of newly onboarded students, interns, and novice developers by offering tutoring and mentoring.
- Played a significant part in the creation of the official website, helping with its design and functionality by utilizing HTML,
 CSS, and JavaScript.
- Held presentational meetings to share insightful knowledge and best practices with the team for front-end engineering, security, and design.

EDUCATION

Institute Universitaire LES COURS SONOU, Benin Republic - Second class upper division

2014 - 2017

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science

Relevant Coursework: Mathematics, Data Structures & Algorithms, Boolean Algebra

PROJECTS

Here are some public projects to which I have contributed:

RunYourPool - BETTERPOOL's Frontend Web Developer

SEP 2022 - JAN 2023 ● 5 mos

- Add new features on demand such as re-developing sign-up and pick-sheet user flow, notifications, chats, etc.
- Fix persistent bugs reported by the QA team and <u>Testilio</u> by proposing solutions (E.g., Add old browser support, make more layouts responsive for mobile and tablet users, etc.)
- Work closely with other teams such as Marketing, Design, Backend, Product, and QA teams.
- Participate in code review on the frontend codebase and ensure code consistency and efficiency.

Silverdream - React Developer

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022 • 11 mos

- Built web app using React and NextJs (for SEO benefits)
- Track bugs and view logs. Thus maintaining different releases and deployment
- Work very closely with other teams such as Client, Design, and Backend teams.

Nairgym - React Developer

MAY 2019 - APR 2020 • 12 mos

- A professional education center dedicated to children where they can learn many things. They promote sports for children.
- Bootstrap frontend project using Create React App, and Redux for state management.
- Work closely with other teams such as Marketing, Design, Backend, Product, and QA teams.

React Rapid Carousel - Open Source Developer (NPM) - GitHub repository

SEP 2020 - PRESENT • Published May 2021

- Consider trying this package because React apps deserve an easy-to-integrate yet lightweight Carousel.
- Maintained different releases and got over 79 weekly downloads.